When we buy a health insurance policy
What do we pay for?
I am not talking about the features here
But I am talking about the amount upto which
we get coverage and this
amount is called the sum insured
The more this sum insured our policy will be
The more expensive it will become and the more this sum
The less insured our policy will be
The annual premium will also reduce and
We can take treatment up to this sum insured in the entire year
Companies give us cumulative bonus when
We stay with the same company and get the same
renewal done within the company
No Claim bonus is given to us in health insurance when
we have not filed a claim in the past year
This is fine but the most mysterious feature is
Restoration benefit means once our
Sum Insured money is used up
During any treatment, these companies claim to restore the
And what is even more surprising is
In some plans, this sum is insured
The restoration benefit is unlimited times
The amount will increase as many times as the money runs out
This amount will be restored upto 100% of
Sum Insured. Now here is Health Insurance trap
If you see in these companies that you
Add small benefit to your health insurance plan
Like consumables benefits, that is
non medical items or annual health
Checkup, everything will be charged
Brother, nothing is available for free here
Then this unlimited time restoration
Benefit which is equal to sum insured
How are these companies giving it and that too  in a fixed premium , coverage is unlimited
This kind of hidden
Terms and conditions which are not discussed much
To uncover them, we
We have brought for you the Pol Khol series and today
In this video, we will discuss Tata AIG Medicare Premier
Restoration Benefit secret terms & conditions
The details related to this benefit
Very important terms related to the feature
conditions as in Tata AIG Medicare Plan , Within a year
How many times can you restore your
Amount under the Premier Plan
For the same disease, same illness, same treatment
Will you be able to avail this benefit and assume
That means your entire money has not been used
If the sum is insured, then even partially
Will the amount be restored or the entire sum
The insured must be over and
Apart from this feature according to the policy terms
Each and every term and condition related to it
In full detail and in depth I will
explain it to you so that you
do not get misled while buying a policy or taking a claim
so let's start this
let's start the video and reveal the truth
restoration of Tata AIG Medicare Premier
The first question about the benefit is
When will this restoration benefit become active?
If it is, then I
I will read this line for you in the policy wordings
We will
Automatically restore the basic sum insured
Upon exhaustion of the sum insured and
Accrued cumulative bonus during the policy
Period This is what I understand that
During the entire policy term, when your
Basic Sum Insured i.e. the amount you
Policy and if you have accumulated any cumulative
Bonus of both of these
Exhausted, when the sum assured is over, you will get
We will give you this restoration benefit
The basic sum insured will be restored again
The second question arises that how many times in a year will this automatic restoration be done?
how many times will this happen in a year? For this,
It is written here that this benefit can be
Availed once during the policy period
Subject to the following conditions i.e.
You can avail the restoration benefit only once in a year
and to do so
you must also follow the terms and conditions given below
If it is necessary to fulfill then let's know this
What are the Terms and Condition through which you
So that everyone can understand this feature in a better way
I will read the first condition for you
The Restored Sum Insured can be used for all
Claim by the insured persons who Have not
Claimed earlier under sections b1 to b4. means every
The policy holder can avail automatic restoration of
The amount restored can be used for treatment
But the condition is one
That he has claimed sections b1 to b4 Which
What are their coverages? Have they filed any claim till now?
If they have not taken any section b1 to b4, which are they?
Section b1 has coverage, inpatient coverage is there
Hospitalization means getting admitted and getting treated
If they have not taken section b2, then is
Regarding pre hospitalization expenses
i.e. associated before admission
Expenses section B3 comes post
Hospitalization expenses i.e. post
No claim for hospitalization is filed either
and section b4 comes under
Day care treatments.
These are the treatments for which the patient is not admitted for 24
hours, he is treated in two-four hours
and these
Expenses are also covered as day treatment But
He makes a claim from the insurance company
So if there is a policy holder family
member who has already paid the amount in the policy tenure
by filing a claim under any of these four sections
then he cannot claim the amount from this restoration amount
The money cannot be used for treatment
This is the first condition but the other conditions
It is even more important to understand the second condition
It says in case the insured has
Claimed under these sections then this happens automatically
Restoration benefit is available for
Admissions due to unrelated illnesses and diseases
This means that if a policy holder
has previously taken a claim under section b1 to b4
he can still avail restoration benefit
If you want to do it then you can use the money for an unrelated illness or disease.
You can use this money for the illness or disease.
That is, for the treatment for which
First use the money for the treatment of the disease.
It happened and it got exhausted.
This amount of restoration cannot be used for the same disease
This amount of restoration cannot be used for
In the third condition, you can use it for the same
Disease also
So let's read the third condition how
However this benefit is for related illness and
Disease would be available in case of claim
Insured person for admission after 45 days From the date of discharge of earlier Claim.
Means if any policy holder is suffering from the same disease and want to
Use the amount of restoration
If he wants, then whatever treatment he has taken in the past
related to this disease
whatever hospitalization he had in the past
And from there when he is discharged from the hospital
You got it 45 days after that discharge
Also related to the same illness, same disease Restoration amount can be used
Now this means that there will be a major treatment
in which your sum assured gets exhausted
If the same treatment Related You need more money
You need restoration amount in your policy
If you want to use previous
In the previous treatment when you
You can use this restoration money for 45
days from the time of discharge from the hospital
Cannot use it only after that
Amount will be available for you
fourth I will read the condition for you in case of Family floater policy reinstatement of sum
Insured will be available for all
Insured person in The Policy on Floater
Basis means if your health insurance
The policy is a family floater health insurance
The policy is family floater health insurance
The policy means your whole family
It is covered under a common sum insured
That is, if the policy is of ₹ 10 lakh, then that
Out of 10 lakh, all the family members
can use it for treatment
This is not ₹ 10 lakh for everyone, this is a common sum insured
So if you have taken a policy on family floater basis
If you have bought the policy then your restoration The amount that will be restored is a common benefit
It will come on a floater basis, it will be same for everyone
The amount will be common
Everyone can use it, this is the fifth condition. This benefit shall Be applicable annually for
Policies with tenure of more than one year
This means that if you have bought a long term policy
or bought a two or three year policy then
It is not so that we can avail the restoration benefit three times in the first year
Every
Restoration benefit year on year
Basis you can avail long term
In policies you can avail this benefit in pre-pone or
Cannot be availed simultaneously Sixth
The condition says The Unutilized Restoration
Sum insured cannot be carried forward
That is, if the amount in your policy is restored once
and it is not used for the whole year
then you can carry it forward
to the next year's renewal
You get fresh restoration amount every year
You will get the amount and all these terms and conditions
These conditions are on year to year basis
If anything of the previous year is applicable
The amount is still left
It cannot be added to next year
The seventh and last condition is that
This benefit shall not be
Applicable on global coverage i.e. Indian
If you are outside the geographical limit
And you want to use restoration benefit. then it is not covered in this policy
For that, your basic sum insured
If you have taken global coverage, then it will be limited to that
The restoration benefit cannot
Be used for global coverage now what I have said here
I have told you each and every term and condition TATA AIG Medicare Premier's policy
I have told you this from the policy wordings document
That means the insurance company has nothing to hide.
It has written in the same font size in which The rest of terms and conditions
Information about coverage and exclusions is written
In the same font size as the
restoration Terms and conditions of benefits are also written
But the problem is when we buy health
Insurance policy from agent, online or offline then we discuss like that
This policy is of lakhs, if it ends then
10 lakhs will come again but these
The terms and conditions of getting ₹  10 lakh again
Neither we are interested to know them
And obviously
The Insurance company will not shout about them
They will not tell because if they do so
It may affect the sales of their policy
Then who will ask about these terms ?
Whose responsibility is it brother, whose policy is this ?
It is ours, whose restore benefit is ? ours
Who will pay the premium ? we will
Who will use these benefits at the time of claim ?
If we do it, then all these terms and conditions
It is also our responsibility to know
If you like the information given in the video then
To show your love and support you
You can like the video and the channel
You can also subscribe and wherever necessary Do share the information given in the video
In the next video of Pol Khol series ,
Which insurance plan's feature
Would you like to reveal ?  mention this also in the comment . I Harvinder Singh
I take your permission, I will see you in the next video
Till then take care of yourself, be happy
Stay well and stay healthy Jai Hind